Guide to the National Association of Elementary School Principals, 1927-2015 MS2364
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
National Association of Elementary School Principals
1927-2014
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
National Association of Elementary School Principals (U.S.)
MS2364
25 Linear Feet
The NAESP is dedicated to developing principals' professional skills in order to improve the quality of children's educations. The collection includes the organization's publications, recordings and documents from annual conferences and events, and governing documents such as bylaws and platforms.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Arrangement
For Collection: Organized into 3 series: Conferences and Events, Governance, and Events.
Series: Arranged aphabetically by title and chronologically within titles.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the records and publications of the National Association of Elementary School Principals. The material dates from 1927-2015. The collection is organized into three separate series, which include Conferences and Events, Governance, and Publications.
Biographical / Historical
The National Association of Elementary School Principals was first organized by a group of 51 elementary school principals at the February 1921 meeting of the National Education Association's Department of Superintendence. In July of that year the group decided to join the NEA as the Department of Elementary School Principals. They established an office at the NEA's headquarters in 1931. In January of 1970 the organization's membership, now over 25,000, voted to become an affiliate of the NEA and to change its name back to the National Association of Elementary School Principals. The group is now headquartered in Alexandria, Virginia. The NAESP publishes Principal magazine and several professional newsletters, in addition to holding workshops and conferences aimed at professional development. The NAESP is dedicated to developing principals' professional skills in order to improve the quality of children's educations.
Elementary school principals; Education -- United States -- History; Education policy
- Conferences and Events, 1982-2013; Series 1; 4 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  The materials included in this series have to do with the NAESP's annual conferences or other events significant to the association. The materials date from 1982 to 2013. This series contains convention newspapers, event pamphlets and programs, photographs and negatives, powerpoints on zip drives and CDs, speeches recorded on 3 ½" floppy discs and VHS tapes, and interviews recorded on VHS tapes. Notable materials include several presidential addresses to the NAESP, an interview with the association's former Executive Director Sam Sava, and photos and videos from the annual National Distinguished Principals awards ceremony.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged alphabetically by title, and chronologically within titles.
  - Aspiring Principals Program, Undated; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Convention News, 1983-1985, 1987; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Convention News, 1988-1989; Series 1 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Convention News, 1990; Series 1 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Convention News, 1991; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Convention News, 1992; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Convention News, 1993; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Convention News, 1994; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Convention News, 1995-1996; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Convention News, 1997; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Convention News, 1998; Series 1 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Convention News, 1999; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Convention News, 2000; Series 1 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Convention News, 2001; Series 1 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Convention News, 2002; Series 1 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Daniel Goleman, March 21, 1999; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Dedication NAESP Headquarters program, 1986; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Delegate Assembly, 2006; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Department of Elementary School Principals News Conference Special, April 1969; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Hillary Rodham Clinton address to NAESP, 1996; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Leading Learning Communities, February 11, 2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous photographs and negatives, undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - NAESP Awards dinner, 1988; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - National Distinguished Principals award photos 4685-4686, 2002; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - National Distinguished Principals award photos 4687-4688, 2002; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - National Distinguished Principal Awards, October 9, 1998; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - National Distinguished Principals awards program, Undated; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - National Distinguished Principals Awards White House ceremony and press conference, October 18, 1989; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - National Distinguished Principals highlights and awards ceremony, October 6, 2000; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - National Distinguished Principals hightlights and awards ceremony, 2002; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - National Distinguished Principals highlights and awards ceremony, 2003; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - National Distinguished Principals highlights and awards ceremony, October 29, 2004; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - National Distinguished Principals photo wall, 2004; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - National Distinguished Principals program, 2007; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - National Distinguished Principals program, 2013; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - National Distinguished Principals Program with Sam Sava, Undated; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - National Distinguished Principals Program White House ceremony, October 18, 1989; Series 1 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - National Distinguished Principals promotional video and awards ceremony, September 20, 1996; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - National Distinguished Principals receiving pins and Frank A. Young party, October 1998; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - National Distinguished Principals speech, 2010; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - National Distinguished Principals Standards Session 1, 2001; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - National Distinguished Principals Standards Session 2 with interviews, 2001; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - National Distinguished Principals Standards session interviews, continued, 2001; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - National Distinguished Principal VIP photos 4690-4691, 2002; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - National Distinguished Principals White House ceremony with Dr. Sava and President Bush, October 1989; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - National Fellows Program, 1983, 1986-1987; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - President Bush video message to NAESP, 1990; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - President Bush video message to NAESP, 1992; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - President Clinton NAESP Convention, March 1, 1995; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - President Clinton remarks for NAESP, March 5, 1998; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Sam Sava, March 20, 1999; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Sava Speech, 1999; Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Scholars Seminar programs, 1986-1987; MS2364 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - State Leaders Conference programs [1/2], 1977, 1982-1999; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - State Leaders Conference programs [2/2], 1977, 1982-1999; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Third Ward Elementary Hero's Hall of Fame Roger Bolyard, 2002; Series 1 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Tom Peters, March 22, 1999; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - US Department of Education Principals Leadership Summit - Three Portraits of Instructional Leadership, July 2000; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - William Jefferson Clinton address to NAESP, 1997; Series 1 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - William Jefferson Clinton address to NAESP, July 25, 1997; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Governance, 1943-2014; Series 2; 6.25 Linear Feet
  This series includes materials relevant to the NAESP's membership, bylaws and guidelines, constitution, and organizational development planning. They date between 1943 and 2014. The materials are primarily pamphlets, brochures, and bound reports, in addition to several VHS tapes. Notable materials include the organization's bylaws and platform, tributes to former directors, and documents from the Vision 2021 strategic guide, which contains the association's plans for development, organization, and budgeting.
  The series is arranged alphabetically by title and chronologically within titles.
  - Annual Report, 1971; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bylaws, 1943; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Bylaws, 1953; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Bylaws, 1959; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Bylaws, 1975, 1977, 1979; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Bylaws, 1980; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bylaws, 1980; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 1961-1964, 1966; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 1969-1970; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - History of the South Central District, Undated; Series 2 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Long-range strategic plan 1987-1992 [1/2], undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Long-range strategic plan 1987-1992 [2/2], undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Long-range strategic plan 1992-1997, undated; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Long-range strategic plan 1998-2003, Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Membership Directory, 1992; Series 2 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Membership directory, 1996; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Membership directory, 2000; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Membership directory and annual report, 1972; Series 2 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Platform, 1973-1979; Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Platform [1/7], 1981, 1985; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Platform [2/7], 1986-1987; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Platform [3/7], 1988-1989; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Platform [4/7], 1990-1994; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Platform [5/7], 1995-1997; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Platform [6/7], 1998-1999; Series 2 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Platform, 2002; Series 2 (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Platform, 2003; Series (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Platform, 2004; Series (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Platform [7/7], 2011; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Report of staff committee on problems of transition to the new constitutional convention documents, January 19, 1972; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Revised membership statistical report, 2000; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Strategic long-range plan 1982-1987 [1/2], July 1982; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Strategic long-range plan 1982-1987 [2/2], July 1982; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Strategic long-range plan 1982-1987, revised January 1983, Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Tribute to Ed Keller, July 1994; Series 2 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Tribute to Sam Sava, undated; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Vision 2021 intermediate goals 2011-2014, budget summary 2013-2014, Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Vision 2021 NAESP strategic framework 2008-2011, Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Vision 2021 strategic growth plan 2014-2017, annual budget 2015-2016, undated; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Vision 2021 progress report: gaining momentum, 2014; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Vision 2021 transformations in leading, learning, and community, 2008; Series 2 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Publications, 1927-2014; Series 3; 14.25 Linear Feet
  This series is the largest of the NAESP collection and is comprised of news, pedagogic and professional development guidelines, educational materials, public service announcements, articles, and research studies published by the NAESP. Materials date from 1927 to 2015. Formats include serialized newsletters, newspapers, glossy color magazines, bound reports, pamphlets, brochures, bound studies, books, and journals, spiral-bound reports, workbooks, a 5" floppy disc, VHS tapes, powerpoint presentations on CD, BETACAM, and a U-matic tape. Notable materials include a series of bound studies of the elementary school principalship done every ten years, the association's monthly newspaper Communicator, manuscripts of the editorial newsletter Dateline, and Principal magazine.
  - The Administrative Team vol. 1 no. 1-2, 1971, 1972; Series 3 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - And proudly serve...as a principal, March 1947; Series 3 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Assuring quality education for American youngsters overseas, Undated; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Bulletin of the Department of Elementary School Principals [1/2], October 1927; Series 3 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Bulletin of the Department of Elementary School Principals [2/2], October 1927; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Celebrating over 70 years of service to K-8 principals, Undated; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Centerfold Seminar, March 1982, undated; Series 3 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Changing lives through the principalship, 2003; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Communications for quality leadership, 1985; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Communicator, August-September 1977, April 1981-April 1982; Series 3 (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Communicator, May 1982-April 1984; Series 3 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Communicator, April 1988, October 1996-February 1997; Series 3 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Communicator, June 1984; Series 3 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Communicator, September 1984-April 1986; Series 3 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Communicator, May 1986-March 1988; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Communicator, May 1988-February 1990; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Communicator, March 1990-June 1991; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Communicator, September 1991-March 1993; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Communicator, April 1993-April 1995; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Communicator, May 1995-September 1996; Series 3 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Communicator, March 1997-October 1997; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Communicator, November 1997-April 1998; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Communicator, May/June 1998-May/June 1999; Series 3 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Communicator, September 1999-December 2000; Series 3 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Communicator, January 2001-December 2001; Series 3 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Communicator, January 2002-November 2002, September 2004; Series 3 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Communicator, December 2002-June 2004; Series 3 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Communicator, November 2004-December 2005; Series 3 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Communicator, December 2005-June 2006; Series 3 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Communicator, September 2006-March 2007; Series 3 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Communicator, April 2007-June 2008; Series 3 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Communicator, September 2008-December 2009; Series 3 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Communicator, November 2008; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Communicator, March 2010, March 2011, March 2013, March 2014; Series 3 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Dateline NAESP, July 1991; Series 3 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Dateline, August 1999; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Dateline, October 1999; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Dateline, December 1999; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Dateline, April 2000; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Dateline, August 2000; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Dateline, October 2000; Series 3 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Dateline, December 2000; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Dateline, April 2001; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Dateline, August 2001; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Dateline, October 2001; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Dateline, December 2001; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Dateline, April 2002; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Dateline, August 2002; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Dateline, October 2002; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Dateline, December 2002; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Dateline, April 2003; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Dateline, August 2003; Series 3 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Dateline, October 2003; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Dateline, December 2003; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Dateline, August 2004; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Distinguished Achievement Award, Communicator, 2002; Series 3 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Dateline feedback, November 2002; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Early childhood education and the elementary school principal, 1990; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Early childhood education and the elementary school principal, 1998; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Early childhood education manuscripts, 1990; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Early childhood education manuscripts and notes, 1989-1996, 2001; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Early education disk, Undated; Series 3 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - The Education Almanac, 1984; Series 3 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - The Education Almanac, 1986; Series 3 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - The Education Almanac, 1988; Series 3 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Effective teachers: effective evaluation in America's elementary and middle schools, 1988; Series 3 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Elementary education and the academically talented pupil, 1961; Series 3 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - The elementary school: Humanizing? Dehumanizing?, 1971; Series 3 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - The Elementary School Journal, October 1963-March 1964; Series 3 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - The Elementary School Journal, April-May 1964, October 1964-January 1965; Series 3 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - The Elementary School Journal, February-May 1965, October-November 1965; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - The Elementary School Journal, December 1965, February-May 1966, October 1966; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - The Elementary School Journal, November 1966, January-March 1967; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - The Elementary School Journal, May 1967, October-December 1967; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - The Elementary School Journal, January 1968, May 1974, January 1975, March 1975, May 1975; Series 3 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - The Elementary School Journal, October 1975-February 1976; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - The elementary school principal plans for safe living, 1944; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - The elementary school principalship - a research study, 1958; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - The elementary school principalship in 1968, Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - The elementary school principalship in 1978: a research study, Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - The elementary school principalship - planning the future, 1945; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - The elementary school principalship - today and tomorrow [1/2], 1948; Series 3 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - The elementary school principalship - today and tomorrow [2/2], 1948; Series 3 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Essentials for principals: creating physical and emotional security in schools, 2002; Series 3 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Essential for principals: data-based decision-making, 2001; Series 3 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Essentials for principals: developing and maintaining high staff morale, 2003; Series 3 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Essentials for principals: effective teacher observations, 2002; Series 3 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Essentials for principals: how to interview, hire, and retain high-quality new teachers, 2000; Series 3 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Essentials for principals: meeting the challenges of high-stakes testing, 2001; Series 3 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Essentials for principals: school leader's guide to special education, 2001; Series 3 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Essentials for principals: strengthening the connection between school and home, 2001; Series 3 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Facilitator workshop for principals, 2007; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Focus on finance, 1987-1993; Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Focus on finance, 1993-2000; Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Focus on finance directory, January 27, 2000; Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Getting started in global education, 1982; Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Here's How, September 1982-December 1987; Series 3 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Here's How, 1999-2003; Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Facts about NAESP, Undated; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Here's How, September 1982-December 1987; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Here's How, February 1988-August 1993; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Here's How, October 1993-June 1999; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - hm Study Skills Program level A grades 1-2, 1991; Series 3 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - hm Study Skills Program level B grades 3-4, 1988; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - How to know and how to use your community, 1941; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Ideas that work: successful programs and practices from the 2002 national distinguished principals, Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Ideas that work: successful programs and practices from the 2003 national distinguished principals, Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Ideas that work: successful programs and practices from the 2005 national distinguished principals, Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Ideas that work: successful programs and practices from the 2006 National Distinguished Principals, Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Ideas that work: successful programs and practices from the 2007 national distinguished principals, Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Ideas that work: successful programs and practices from the 2008 national distinguished principals, Series 3 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Implementing idea: a guide for principals, 2001; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Improving America's schools: developing strong principals to get better results, Undated; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Informe por los padres, Undated; Series 3 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Index to Principal magazing volumes 67-76 (September 1987 through May 1997, Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Inspired! A collection of favorite quotes for elementary and middle-level principals, Undated; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Introduction to publications directory, 1990; Series 3 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Join us!, Undated; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - The K-8 principal in 2008: A 10 year study, 2009; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Leadership Compass, 2003-2006; Series 3 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Leadership matters, 2013; Series 3 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Leading early childhood learning communities executive summary, 2005; Series 3 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Leading learning communities, 2002; Series 3 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Leading after-school learning communities, 2006; Series 3 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Leading after-school learing communities executive summary, 2006; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Leading early childhood learning communities, 2005; Series 3 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Leading early childhood learning communities, Undated; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Leading learning communities executive summary, 2008; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Leading learning communities standards for what principals should know and be able to do, 2008; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Leading pre-K-3 learning communities, 2014; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Leading the way, June- July 1999, September 1999, December 1999; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Leading the way, March/April 2000, June 2000-October 2001, December 2001; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Leading the Way, November 2001; Series 3 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Leads for Locals, March 1958, April 1959, December 1961, March 1964, September 1965; Series 3 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Making the most of after-school time, 2005; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Middle Matters, 1993-1999; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Middle Matters, 1999-2004; Series 3 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Middle Matters correspondence, March 8, 2005; Series 3 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Middle Matters directory, Undated; Series 3 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Module two: hm Study Skills Program level 1 grade 5-7, 1991; Series 3 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - NAESP's federal relations, 1982; Series 3 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - NAESP financial newsletter, 1982-1986; Series 3 (Box 43, Folder 9)